Christopher Parry

15 Beltony Drive, Crewe, Cheshire, CW1 4TX
07476 647826

D.O.B - 1st July 1981

HYPERLINK "mailto:chrisparry07@live.co.uk" chrisparry07@live.co.uk

Profile:

A highly experienced, talented and motivated Operations Manager with over 10 years experience in a fast pace logistics / warehouse environment. Extensive knowledge of the healthcare waste sector, including legislation surrounding transportation of hazardous waste by road

Key Skills:

Excellent man management
Proven ability to work under pressure
Time management
Leadership
Team player

Key Successes:

Consistently increased depot Productivity by over 10 points against budget Successfully achieved WAMITAB accreditation.

Project managed new warehouse from renovation to moving in.

Implementation of a new healthcare waste contract which consisted of over 1500 new customers.

Qualifications:

COTC – Managing the transfer of hazardous wastes (Sept 2010) ADR – Class 6 and 7 Train the Trainer 13 GCSE's grades A-C including Mathematics, English and Science

Career History:

<u>Warehouse Manager – Gist Ltd, March 2013 – July 2018</u>

Assist the operation to ensure the delivery of all product to food retail stores inside the

specified time restriction

Duties Include;

Drive productivity within the warehouse.

Budget Management – main area of control: Hours

Strive to ensure H&S and best practices are adhered to

Build excellent relationships with both customers and suppliers

Manage over 200 FTE's and Agency employees to achieve daily, weekly and monthly targets

Ensure both ambient and cold chain chambers achieve daily 'pick' targets. Ambient daily targets on average 25,000 units and cold chain 40,000 (day cycle only) – Peak seasons over 100,000 units

Recruitment, appraisal, disciplinary and grievance hearings

Team briefings

Investigations – Personal accidents or disciplinary

Achieve yearly objectives set by GM

<u>Transport Manager – Gist Ltd, July 2011 – March 2013</u>

To ensure that all stores received their food delivery inside their allotted 15 minute delivery window

Duties include;

Budget management – main area of control: wages, fuel and vehicle damage Ensure at least 97% of all vehicles arrive at store within a 15 minute window Intake day 1 and delivery day 2 – ALL planned product must be delivered to the correct stores leaving clear warehouse for cycle to be repeated

Ensure the correct trailers are planned for each store (Artic, Rigid, Double Deck etc)

Plan routes for each store reducing mileage and to increase vehicle fill

Liaise with recruitment agency to ensure all vehicles have drivers who also hold suitable licence depending on vehicle

Ensure drivers comply with legislation

Recruitment, appraisal, disciplinary and grievance hearings

Investigations – Personal and vehicle accidents or disciplinary

Achieve yearly objectives set by GM

Operations Manager – Intercare Distribution Services Ltd, July 2004 – March 2011

Collect healthcare waste from over 2500 weekly customers using a team of multi drop delivery drivers. The waste was then returned to our transfer site where it was segregated, stored and presented for further collection and incineration

Duties include;

Ensure all customers are collected on a weekly basis

Regularly review waste runs

Ensure drivers, vehicles and customers comply with legislation

Provide training to both staff and customers regarding the correct presentation and

transportation of healthcare waste including consignment notes

Provide consumables to customers ensuring they comply with legislation

Ensure the transfer station is run in compliance with licence set out by the Environment Agency

Provide quarterly returns to Environment Agency

Complete strategic objectives set by board of directors

Hold monthly team meetings and implement change

Drive company values through the business

Manage budgets over £1,000,000.00

Maintain and manage stock levels, source new and maintain good relationships with current suppliers

On occasions liaise with companies wanting to use our transfer site

Sales Manager – Fitness First Health Club, September 2002 – July 2004

Run a small sales team whose sole purpose is to generate new business for the health club.

Duties include;

Push sales team to generate new leads
Manage performance based on daily, weekly and monthly targets
Guide and train underperforming members of the team
Perform tours of the facilities to prospective new members
Attend events and local businesses to promote health and fitness

References available on request